# Wil Buchanan

williamjamesbuchanan@gmail.com | 863-259-0202 | linkedin.com/in/williamjamesbuchanan | wijabu.github.io

#### EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

An aspiring full-stack web developer with six years of technical solutions experience in the hospitality industry. A curious and creative problem solver pivoting careers and bringing diverse experience from both military and civilian positions with superb interpersonal communication skills.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

LMS, Inc. Mar 2017 – Feb 2023

Six-year contractor with Princess Cruises. Created department to test and fix guest data for the billion-dollar OceanMedallion program

### Director, Data Integrity Experience Operations

July 2021 – Feb 2023

- Directed six Data Analysts; investigated and resolved inconsistencies between SQL and NoSQL databases
- Led Data Integrity Pod through Agile development of PII security and consistency throughout ecosystem
- Scripted JavaScript toolset to automate fixes to common issues; reduced incident resolution time by 75%

## Project Manager & Application Support Lead

Sep 2019 - July 2021

- Designed holistic Jira roadmap tracking hundreds of user stories and epics; provided real-time status to VPs
- Piloted weekly cross-functional meeting; analyzed issue trends with developers; defined priority of solutions
- Compiled APIs to simulate Guest Experience; tested via JavaScript; uncovered gaps among microservices

#### Senior Technical Integration Specialist & Business Analyst

Mar 2017 – Sep 2019

- Tested the Guest Experience in a live production environment; recorded new friction points and use cases
- Published dozens of text and video training materials; trained fellows on resolution of common problems
- Tracked, managed, and solved incidents via ServiceNow; integrated with PagerDuty to automate alerting

#### Public Affairs Superintendent – Florida Air National Guard

Sep 2018 – May 2023

Retired. Spent 13 years in Public Affairs reporting on military deployments, hurricane recovery and COVID-19 vaccine distribution

- Trained journalists in AP style, content creation and media relations; oversaw reporting on 200+ ANG events
- Built cloud-based dynamic schedule to centralize mission organization; reduced man hours by 60%
- Managed 48 Airmen across 14 counties to distribute 87,083 COVID-19 vax for Operation Warp Speed

#### **EDUCATION**

Web Development Bootcamp – Full-stack web applications – Udemy	2023
Master of Arts – Cognitive Science & Interpersonal Communication – University of Central Florida	2013
Bachelor of Arts – Journalism – University of Central Florida	2009

#### LANGUAGES, SKILLS AND TOOLS

-	JavaScript	<ul><li>Express</li></ul>	<ul> <li>ServiceNow</li> </ul>
-	HTML	■ SQL	<ul> <li>Jira / Confluence</li> </ul>
-	CSS	<ul><li>MongoDB</li></ul>	<ul><li>Agile</li></ul>
	NodeJS	■ Git / GitHub	

# SKILL SETS, TRAINING & CERTIFICATIONS + OTHER SKILL SETS

List, these, out, with commas, just, like, this...
\*I made all the font a dark gray color and turned the things that I want to stand out to black